

Aashish Kumar

Nationality: Indian ☐ (+91) 8448618646 **Date of birth:** 01/08/1998 **Gender:** Male

☐ **Email address:** aashish122001@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/aashishk1998

Address: 15-A, Ashok Vihar, Phase 3 Extension, Gurugram (India)

ABOUT ME

A strong business development professional with a demonstrated history of **3.5 years of experience** in developing E-Commerce solutions (B2B and B2C) based on SAP Commerce. Interested in developing technical solutions using software development skills to solve business problems and generate impact at scale. I rely on accountability, articulation and empathy to complement my technical know-how and has helped me play significant roles as a part of a team to drive results and progress. My resilient efforts to find a solution in times of need give me confidence to take responsibility.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate - Projects

Cognizant Technology Solutions [27/12/2023 - Present]

Client: Johnson & Johnson Vision

City: Gurugram
Country: India

- This project aims at providing support to J&J Surgical Vision website for the US and OUS markets.
- Worked on resolving tickets within specified timeframe raised through IRIS portal.
- Responsible for monitoring of cronjobs on daily basis and reporting issues.
- Supported launching of new products on the website.
- o Performing health checks for the websites.

Consultant

Ernst & Young LLP [13/03/2023 - 22/12/2023]

Client: Shree Cement Limited

City: Gurugram **Country:** India

- Developed a persona-driven app universe in flutter using SAP Commerce Cloud to digitalize the entire sales process including sales officers and extended B2B customers and partners.
- Responsible for comprehending business requirements and developing a CRM suite solution for SCL Delivery.
- Extensively collaborated on the OOC module to create RESTful web services and APIs, which are consumed by the Flutter framework using Dart language for the SCL Mobile app.
- Integration Worked on Inbound integration for fetching the data from third-party system and updating in the database.
- Tasks include analysis and design, writing Java code, performing unit testing, releasing code to development and QA Performed. Involved in Feature Enhancements and bug fixing.
- Developed Network Addition Plan for different personas.
- Implemented search restrictions tailored to different personas.
- \circ Managed daily builds and deployments on CCV2, including production deployment and hot fixes.
- Developed In-App Notifications for different modules.
- Developed Custom workflows and approvals across different personas.
- Developed technical assistance for customer complaints and feedback.
- Worked on paginated APIs for multiple filters.

- Performance monitoring and exception analysis through Dynatrace for production.
- Customization of Hybris Data Modeling and OOTB codes as per project requirement.
- Extensively used Hybris Administrative Console (HAC) for initialization, updating system and flexible search query execution.
- Creating story level documentation for future releases.

Digital Tech Developer Analyst

Accenture Pvt. Ltd. [01/04/2022 - 12/03/2023]

Client: Smart Daimler City: Gurugram Country: India

- This B2C project aims to launch a new product range under a new brand of fully digitized and electrical vehicles in 2023, all produced in China. The business model is based on direct sales and e-commerce.
- o Individual contribution in development of primary business functionalities in release.
- o Involved in enhancement, maintenance and bug fixing.
- Completed multiple user stories and delivered within the fleeting period span.
- Involved in writing Junit test classes and increasing SonarQube test coverage to 80%.
- o Creating story level documentation for future releases.
- Handling data using UI Backoffice tools and search engines such as SOLR.
- Worked closely with business stakeholders, understanding their requirements and translating them into technical specifications.

Digital Tech Developer Associate

Accenture Pvt. Ltd. [01/02/2021 - 01/04/2022]

Client: Appease AO City: Gurugram Country: India

- This B2C project handles the complete e-commerce business portfolio brands of H&M i.e., COS, ARKET, &Other Stories, MONKI and Weekday. Provides support to the website.
- Individual contribution in development of primary business functionalities in release.
- Involved in enhancement, maintenance and bug fixing.
- Fixing site issues and incidents raised by the customer.
- Processing stuck Orders.
- Adept with HAC, Backoffice UI tools, Product and Content Catalogs and writing impex scripts.
- Facilitated productive discussion and contributed valuable insights to cross-functional teams, fostering efficient problem-solving.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelors in Technology

Amity University, Gurugram

Field(s) of Study: Information Technology

Final Grade: 7.5

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C2

DIGITAL SKILLS

Microsoft Office / Microsoft Excel / IntelliJ IDEA / GIT Hub / SAP Hybris (2211, 2205, 2105) / Java / Git / SonarQube / Spring MVC / OCC RESTFUL Web Services / HTML / SQL / Ant / Postman / JIRA / Confluence / Hybris (SAP Commerce Cloud/SAP CX – 1905 / 2011 / 2105 versions) – B2C & B2B Accelerators / WCMS / Third-Party Integration / Backoffice / HMC / Junit / ServiceNow

CERTIFICATION(S) / ACHIEVEMENT(S)

• SAP Certified Development Professional - SAP Commerce Cloud - 1905/2024

